Guide to the Park Slope Civic Council (PSCC) records BCMS.0083
Brooklyn Collection
Park Slope Civic Council (PSCC) records
1931-2018
1960-2005
Brooklyn Collection
Park Slope Civic Council
Kaiserman, Carl
Wilson, Irene
Lief, Judith
South Brooklyn Board of Trade
BCMS.0083
27.26 Linear Feet in 20 records cartons, 4 document boxes, 2 half document boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 14 flat file folders.
This collection contains materials generated by the Park Slope Civic Council between 1931 and 2018. It chronicles the activities of the Council, including meetings, the Civic News newsletter, grantmaking, fundraising, events, historic district status, and zoning/development proposals. Types of materials include correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, newsletters, news clippings, posters, blueprints, photographs, negatives, and slides.
Scope and Contents
The Park Slope Civic Council records is made up of materials generated by the Park Slope Civic Council (PSCC) administration and members, especially those involved with PSCC's newsletter Civic News and the Board of Trustees. Materials include correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, newsletters, newspaper clippings, photographs, negatives, slides, blueprints, and posters.
Much of the collection is made up of Irene Wilson's correspondence and subject files from when she was editor of Civic News from the 1960s until her retirement in 1976, and Carl Kaiserman's files from the 1980s through the early 2000s. Kaiserman was a PSCC trustee and active in Revitalization of the Southern Area of the Slope (ROSAS). Park Slope House Tour planning and promotional materials from 1959 to 2018 and research materials related to PSCC's Landmark Campaign to receive NYC Landmarks Preservation Commission Historic District designation also make up a significant portion of the collection.
While there are materials dated from the 1930s, this collection does not contain many records from when the organization was the South Brooklyn Board of Trade.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into six series:
Series 1: Irene Wilson papers, 1931-1977, bulk: 1960-1970
Series 2: Carl Kaiserman papers Series 2: Carl Kaiserman papers, 1970-2004
Series 3: Mort Fleischer papers, 1977-2004
Series 4: Park Slope Civic Council Administration, 1938-2009
Series 5: Landmark Campaign Research, circa 1960
Series 6: Civic News Issues, 1938-2018
Historical Note
The Park Slope Civic Council (PSCC) was founded in 1896 as the South Brooklyn Board of Trade, which acted as a chamber of commerce, lobbying the city and state for improvements to infrastructure and services across the geographic area south of Downtown Brooklyn. One of the founders and first president was Alexander G. Calder. In the late 1950s, the South Brooklyn Board of Trade renamed itself the Park Slope Civic Council to increase residents' engagement in the neighborhood.
As the Park Slope Civic Council, the organization regularly publishes the Civic News newsletter, reviews changing building regulations and developments, provides grants to neighborhood projects, and organizes fundraising activities such as the annual House Tour. PSCC acts as a conduit between members and political representatives.
PSCC led the campaign that achieved historic district designation for the section of Park Slope closest to Prospect Park in 1973. The Council continued its historic district advocacy in the late 1990s, planning to expand the historic district designation to the north, south, and west.
In 2001, Revitalization of the Southern Area of the Slope (ROSAS), a neighborhood association active in the neighborhood south of Park Slope since 1978, merged with the Park Slope Civic Council, bringing the activities of both organizations under one umbrella.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Park Slope Civic Council via Judith Lief, Co-President, 2016.
The immediate source of acquisition for some material accessioned by Brooklyn Historical Society in 1991 is unknown.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The majority of the materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org at least two weeks prior to research visit.
Related Materials
Center for Brooklyn History holds the following related collections:
- Everett and Evelyn Ortner papers and photographs (ARC.306)
- Brooklyn neighborhood associations and civic organizations publications (ARC.167)
- Elizabeth Feldhusen collection of Brooklyn ephemera (ARC.299)
The following published materials included in this collection are also cataloged in the Center for Brooklyn History Library's Main Collection:
- Civic News
- Gaynor, William J. South Brooklyn commercially and historically: city subway plan and settlement. 1911.
Blueprints (reprographic copies); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Minutes; Newsletters; Programs (documents); Civic improvement |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Fundraising |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Historic preservation; Neighborhood Associations; Neighborhoods -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Zoning -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Gowanus (New York, N.Y.); Kings County (N.Y.); Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.); Lief, Judith; Park Slope Civic Council; Fourteenth Regiment Armory (New York, N.Y.); Park Slope Civic Council; Revitalization of the Southern Area of the Slope (ROSAS); South Brooklyn Board of Trade
- Series 1: Irene Wilson papers, 1931-1977; 1960-1970
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged into three sub-series:
  Sub-series 1.1: Subject Files, 1931-1975
  Sub-series 1.2: Correspondence, 1960-1977
  Sub-series 1.3: Civic News Production, 1946-1973
  Biographical Note
  Irene Wilson was editor of Civic News for 16 years from the 1960s until 1976. Before working for Civic News, Irene Wilson received degrees from Wellesley College and Harvard University, and taught college English. She lived in Montana for a period of time, working as a cowboy and writing poetry and fiction for magazines. When Wilson moved back east, she found an apartment in Manhattan. Wilson moved to Park Slope when she learned her apartment building was to be demolished along with Penn Station. Her friend and Park Slope Civic Council trustee, Bob Makla, found Wilson the apartment in Park Slope and asked Wilson to write for Civic News. Wilson also held a Guest Editor position before taking on the role of Editor. Irene Wilson died in December 1983.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1: Irene Wilson papers, 1931-1977, includes article drafts, handwritten notes, correspondence, and news clippings from the work of Irene Wilson, Civic News Editor and contributor in the 1960s and 1970s.
  This series also includes subject files and correspondence related to the Prospect Park Handbook, a guide to and history of Prospect Park. Wilson was to be credited as editor and author on the Handbook, but it is unclear whether it was ever published.
  - Sub-series 1.1: Subject Files, 1931-1975; 1960-1969
    The sub-series is arranged alphabetically.
    - 78th Precinct Community Council - South Brooklyn Community Council, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Addresses, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - [A Guide to Family Nutrition], circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Airplane Crash, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Airplane Crash, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Airplane Crash, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - [Art], circa 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7, Box 24, Folder 1)
    - [Art], 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - [Arts], 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arts, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - [Arts], 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - [Arts], 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Animal Welfare, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Banks, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14, Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Blockbusting, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blockbusting, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Boathouse and Miscellaneous, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bridges, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Brooklyn Colonial History (Clippings), circa 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Brooklyn History, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Brooklyn Maritime + Railroads, Plus Furs, Jewelry + Other Industries, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - [The Brownstone Gallery, Jerome Burns invitation], 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - [Brownstones], 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - [Bruce North, Brooklyn Museum Art School], circa 1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Central Park, circa 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Churches, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Churches, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Civic Fights for or Against, Expressway, Supermarkets, New Markets, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Civil Defence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Civil Liberties, Rights, etc., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Civil Rights, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Civil Rights, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Clubs, Associations, Civic Groups, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Community Centers, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - [Con Edison], circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Coney Island, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - [Crime], 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - [Crime], 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - [Crime and Police], 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Crime and Police, Traffic, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Department of City Planning [City Planning Commission], 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Department of City Planning [City Planning Commission], 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Foundations, 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Gardens, Trees, Pets, Etc., 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Geology, 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Greater New York Savings Bank, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Historic Preservation Newspaper Clippings, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - History, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - History of Brooklyn - Demand for Park, Donald Simeon, circa 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - [History - Old-timers], 1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - History - Old-timers, 1964-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Home Tour, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 27, Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Hospitals, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Housing, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - [Housing], 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Housing, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Housing, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Housing, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Housing, 1962-1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Housing - Watchdog Committee, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Park Slope Housing + Renewal, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - International and Churches, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - International and Churches, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - [International Ladies Garment Workers Union], 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - [Jobs], 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Library, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Library, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Library, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Library, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Lights, Street Traffic, 1958-1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Medical, July '64, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Memorials, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Merchants, 1931-1963 (Box 3, Folder 15, Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Mortgages, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Museum, 1961-1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Music, 1961-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Music + Culture Venues NYC, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Narcotics, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Neighborhood Conservation, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Neighborhood Conservation, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Newspapers, Late 1960s, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - [Operation Sail], 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Organizations and Clubs, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3, Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Organizations - Brooklyn, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Other Brooklyn Neighborhoods, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - ["Our Prospect Park Zoo" Article], circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - [Philosophy], 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Playgrounds and Camps, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - [Police], 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - [Police], 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - [Politics], 1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Politics, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Politics, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Prospect Park Booklets and Handbook, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - [Prospect Park Handbook], circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Prospect Park Presentation, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 16, Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Prospect Park [Tree Tour], circa 1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - [Public Housing], 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Real Estate, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Recreation, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Revolutionary War Park Slope, circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - [Robert Barry, Park Slope Civic Council President], 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Schools, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Schools, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Schools, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - [Schools], 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - [Schools], 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Schools, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Schools, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Schools, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - [Schools], 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - [Schools], 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7, Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Scouts, Girl + Boy, 1961-1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Slumlords, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Snow, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - [Stables in Prospect Park], circa 1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - [St. Francis Xavier Youth Center], 1962 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - St. John's Place, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - [Subway], 1963 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - [Traffic], 1962 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Traffic, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - [Trees], circa 1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Trees, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - [Vandalism], 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Young People, Juvenile, Youth Board, etc., 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Young People, Juvenile, Youth Board, etc., 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Youth, 1957-1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - [Youth], 1961 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Youth, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - [Youth], 1964 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Youth, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Youth Leadership Project: SBIC South Brooklyn Improvement Council, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - YMCA, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - [YMCA Prospect Park Branch Report of Study and Planning Committee], 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - [YMCA News: Prospect Park - Bay Ridge Branch], 1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - YWCA, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series 1.2: Correspondence, 1960-1977
    The sub-series is in original order, arranged by correspondent and chronologically.
    Sub-series 1.2: Correspondence, 1960-1977, includes correspondence between Irene Wilson and contributors to Civic News and people involved with the Park Slope Civic Council. Correspondents with a significant amount of material include Elizabeth Van Brunt, a horticulturalist and member of the Brooklyn Botanic Garden governing committee in the 1950s and 1960s, Gladys Arne Holton, a reporter and painter, and Bob Makla, a Trustee of the South Brooklyn Board of Trade and Park Slope Civic Council.
    - Letters, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Letters, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Letters, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Letters, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Letters, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Letters, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Elizabeth Van Brunt, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with Elizabeth Van Brunt, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence with Elizabeth Van Brunt, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with Elizabeth Van Brunt, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Presidents, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Presidents, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Presidents, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Letters, Emilie and John LaCorte, Italian Heritage, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Wilson Associates [correspondence], 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence with Gladys Holton, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence with Gladys and Jim Holton, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Gladys Holton, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Gladys Holton, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Gladys Holton, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Gladys Holton, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Gladys and Jim Holton, 1970-1971 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Dorothy and William Jesinsky, 1964-1966 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - [Correspondence with Bob Wilson], 1970-1971 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - [Correspondence with Bob Wilson], 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Civic News Correspondence - Trustees, 1961-1963 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Personal [correspondence], 1961 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Bob Makla, 1960-1962 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Bob Makla, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Bob Makla, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Bob Makla, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Bob Makla, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Bob Makla: Letters, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Van Brunt Seaman, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters: Civic News Contributors, Park Slope Education Committee, Blockbusting Committee, Tree Committee, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 2, Folder 3)
    - Letters: Civic News Contributors, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letters: Contributors to Civic News, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letters: Civic News Contributors, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Letters: Contributors to Civic News, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Prospect Park (History and Research), circa 1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Prospect Park (History and Research), circa 1967 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Prospect Park (Trees), circa 1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Prospect Park, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Prospect Park, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Armory, Military Monuments, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sub-series 1.2: Correspondence, 1960-1977
  - Sub-series 1.3: Civic News Production, 1946-1973
    The sub-series is in original order.
    Sub-series 1.3: Civic News Production, 1946-1973, includes materials related to publishing the newsletter, such as galley copies, draft logos for the Park Slope Civic Council, color swatches, handwritten notes with ideas for articles and issues, and notes from PSCC meetings Wilson attended regarding Civic News.
    - Civic Council: Membership Drives, etc., 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Civic News Content Pages, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council Officers], 1964 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - [Notes about Civic News Publication], circa 1963 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council Membership Form], 1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - [Civic News Mailing Envelopes], 1962-1967 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Civic News Copies [Subscription Communications], 1946-1961 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - [Housing Subcommittee], 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - [Trustee Meetings], 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - [The Fund Committee], 1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - [Newsclippings about Park Slope Civic Council meetings], 1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - [Meeting Notes], 1963 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - [Civic News Contributors], circa 1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - [Committees], 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - [Agenda Committee], 1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - [Civic News Ideas Notes], 1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - [Civic News Ideas Notes], circa 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - [Park Slope Cityfair], circa 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - [General Membership Meeting], circa 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - [Important Events Newsletter], circa 1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Civic News Production, circa 1963 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Civic News Production, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Production, 1963-1969 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - [Civic News Galley Copies], 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - [Brooklyn Heights Association Bulletin], 1964 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Series 2: Carl Kaiserman papers, 1970-2004
  Carl Kaiserman was an architect with Rothzeid Kaiserman Thomson and Bee, Park Slope Civic Council Trustee, and an active member in the organization Revitalization of the Southern Area of the Slope (ROSAS). Kaiserman worked with Mort Fleischer, who was PSCC President from 1982-1984 and a Trustee, on PSCC's annual House Tour. His roles as architect and community advocate, took him to several significant sites around Park Slope, such as the Montauk Club, 14th Regiment Armory, and the Pavilion Theater.
  Series 2: Carl Kaiserman papers, 1970-2004 includes the papers of Carl Kaiserman and reflects his work as an architect, a Park Slope Civic Council Trustee, and member of Revitalization of the Southern Area of the Slope (ROSAS). Materials include correspondence, meeting minutes and agendas, news clippings, blueprints, floor plans, and photographs and negatives.
  The sub-series Subject Files, Gowanus Expressway Project, and 14th Regiment Armory include photographs taken by Carl Kaiserman of buildings and landmarks around Park Slope for his presentations on "Lost Theatres" and "Lost Mansions" of the neighborhood, as well as documenting sites involved in the Gowanus Expressway Project and 14th Regiment Armory.
  The series is arranged into five sub-series:
  Sub-series 2.1: Meeting Materials, 1978-2002
  Sub-series 2.2: Subject Files, 1946-2005, bulk: 1980-2004
  Sub-series 2.3: Gowanus Expressway Project, 1987-2004
  Sub-series 2.4: 14th Regiment Armory, 1990-2004
  Sub-series 2.5: Revitalization of the Southern Area of the Slope (ROSAS), 1970-2001
  - Sub-series 2.1: Meeting Materials, 1978-2002
    The materials in this sub-series are grouped chronologically, which is the original order.
    Sub-series 2.1: Meeting Materials, 1978-2002, includes agendas, minutes, committee reports, notes, and other supporting documentation from Trustee meetings, public sessions, and other PSCC meetings Kaiserman attended. Civic News issues are interfiled chronologically with the meeting materials.
    - [Trustee meeting agendas and minutes], 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - [Trustee meeting agendas and minutes], 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 32, Box 23, Folder 8)
    - [Trustee meeting notes and agendas], 1998-2001 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - [Trustees directory], 2002 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1978 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1980 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1981 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1982 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1983 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1984 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1988 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1989 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials] includes Methodist Hospital Expansion, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials] includes Methodist Hospital Expansion, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - [Park Slope Civic Council meeting notes and materials], 1993 (Box 16, Folder 1)